# PRASHANT KUMAR

# QUALITY ASSURANCE

(+91) 8506014502

prashantnoer@gmail.com

I'm working as a Software Test Engineer in <a href="Mtech India Pvt. Ltd.">Mtech India Pvt. Ltd.</a> at Gurgaon. I have 5-years and 8-months' experience of website testing in the manual as well as Automation with selenium with Java. I usually deal with selecting test cases for Automation, writing the POM classes, Developing test scripts, Preparing test data, Reviewing the scripts, Integrating frameworks, Analyzing the execution result, Preparing the execution report, Preparing automation-related documents & Execute the test scripts locally.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Core-Java & C.

**Java**: Basic of Core-Java, Access Modifier, Inheritance, Encapsulation, Abstraction, Polymorphism, Interface, Abstract Class, Method Overloading, Method Overriding, Abstraction, Interface, Collection Framework, etc.

**Selenium:** Browser Launching, Writing x-path, Action class, Window Handling, Drop-Down Handling, Handling Mouse Operation, Frame Handling, Pop-Up Handling, Screen-shoot, Scroll down, Scroll Up, Handling Web table, Synchronisation, Batch Execution, Group Execution, Parallel Execution, Hybrid Framework

**Tools**: Apache POI, Test-NG, Selenium Standalone, Chrome Driver, GECKO Driver, SVN, MAVEN & BUGZILLA, etc.

**Manual:** Functional Testing, SDLC, Waterfall Model, Regression Testing & Smoke Testing, etc.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Mtech India Pvt. Ltd. (June-2019 - Present)

Quality Analyst

Techsan India Technology Pvt. Ltd. (2016-19)

Software Test Engineer

#### **EDUCATION**

MASTER OF TECHNOLOGY - (2013-15)

Computer Science and Engineering

UTTRAKHAND TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY DEHRADUN, UTTRAKHAND

**BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - (2008-12)** 

Computer Science and Engineering

MJRP UNIVERSITY JAIPUR RAJASTHAN

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **TITLE - PRODIGIOUS**

## Technologies used:

JAVA, Selenium Web-Driver, TestNG, Maven, JavaScripts, Robot.

## **Description:**

Prodigious HRMS is a system designed to manage the entire range of activities performed by the HR department which includes appointments, appraisals, increments, transfers, leave and attendance, salary generation, TDS on salaries, employee separation, etc.

#### **Activities:**

I've applied Automation (Selenium with Java) on various modules Like - Appointments, Employee Master, Leave, PaySlip generation, etc.

#### TITLE - REQUEST TRACKING

## Technologies used:

JAVA, Selenium Web-Driver, TestNG, Maven, JavaScripts, Robot.

# **Description:**

The request tracking project is based on the CRM domain. In this project, we get opportunities in the form of leads and we need to convert those opportunities into sales. In this project we can create the sales channel, we can create the customer, we can perform the activities like meeting with a customer, interact with the customer through email, phone calls and even if we perform any other activity, we can create that activity and perform.

## **Activities:**

In this project, I've applied Manual & Automation (Selenium with Java) using POM Architecture.

### **TITLE - SALES AND INVOICE**

## Technologies used:

JAVA, Selenium Web-Driver, TestNG, Maven, JavaScripts, Robot.

# **Description:**

The Sales and Invoice project designed to manage order related activities like getting orders for the product, generate an invoice for the purchase. Also to maintain the products like if there is any new product or any new variant for the product we can create that product or variant in the catalog field.

#### **Activities:**

I've applied Manual Testing like Functional, Smoke & Regression.